Finding Aid for First Congregational Church (Morenci, Mich.) records, 1858-1971
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Congregational Church (Morenci, Mich.) records 1858-1971
First Congregational Church (Morenci, Mich.)
2 linear feet
86757 Ba 2
Church established in 1858; its name was later changed to First Congregational United Church of Christ. Parish record books, minutes of board of trustees and congregational society, and records of church women's organizations.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records are on deposit from the church (donor no. 6231 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The First Congregational Church of Morenci was established on March 17, 1858 by a group of people who had formerly worshipped in the Congregational Church of Medini Township. In 1859, the spiritual and temporal elements of the church were separated. A board of trustees was created to care for the church's pecuniary interests while separate officers concerned themselves with the church's spiritual development. Because of overlapping authority and frequent joint meetings, this unique arrangement was terminated in 1894 when the two bodies merged to form a single governing board.
Within the church several small groups have organized themselves. The Woman's Missionary Society was formed in June 1874 by thirteen women interested in promoting the church's missionary efforts both at home and abroad. Subsequently other women, less interested in missionary endeavors, founded the Woman's Union as a social and church fundraising organization. In 1913 the Daughters of the Covenant were founded to aid the pastor in carrying out his work.
The congregation's papers have been divided into two series: the records of the church itself and the records of groups within the church. Most important within the first category are parish record books which contain membership information, financial data and minutes taken at meetings of various boards and at the annual meeting of the entire congregation. The second category includes records of the Woman's Missionary Society, the Woman's Union, and the Daughters of the Covenant.
Subjects:
Congregational churches--Michigan--Morenci.; First Congregational Church (Morenci, Mich.); Morenci (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Morenci--Societies and clubs.; Women--Religious life--Michigan--Morenci.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Churches--Michigan--Morenci.; Congregational churches--Michigan--Morenci.; First Congregational Church (Morenci, Mich.); Morenci (Mich.)--Churches.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Parish records
  - Parish Histories (Box 1)
  - Parish Record Books
    - 1858-1895 (Box 1)
    - 1895-1901 (Box 1)
    - 1932-1945 (Box 1)
    - 1946-1959 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes
    - 1949-1951 (Box 1)
    - 1951-1954 (Box 1)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 1)
    - 1963-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Congregational Society minutes
    - 1859-1897 (Box 1)
    - 1898-1918 (Box 1)
  - Educational Work
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor
      - Record book 1892-circa 1896 (Box 1)
      - Record book 1895-1896 (Box 1)
      - President's book (Box 1)
    - Sunday School Council minutes 1927-1940 (Box 1)
  - Financial Record book 1897-1903 (Box 1)
  - Congregational Messenger 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Church programs 1955-1964 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Parish Societies
  - Woman's Union
    - Record books
      - 1896-circa 1903 (Box 2)
      - 1905-1910 (Box 2)
      - 1911-1915 (Box 2)
      - 1916-1917 (Box 2)
      - 1919-1922 (Box 2)
      - 1927-circa 1928 (Box 2)
      - 1929-1932 (Box 2)
      - 1933-1934 (Box 2)
      - 1935-1936 (Box 2)
      - 1937 (Box 2)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 2)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 2)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 2)
      - 1944 (Box 2)
      - 1945-1947 (Box 2)
      - 1948-1951 (Box 2)
      - 1956-1959 (Box 2)
    - Financial Record book 1926-1949 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Woman's Missionary Society
    - Record books
      - 1898-1910 (Box 2)
      - 1917-1937 (Box 2)
      - 1944-1961 (Box 2)
    - Fellowship booklets 1945-1954 (Box 2)
  - Daughters of the Covenant
    - Record books
      - 1926-1928 (Box 2)
      - 1929-1940 (Box 2)
      - 1940-1944 (Box 2)
      - 1950-1962 (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Photograph of church sanctuary 1949 (Box 2)